Lesson 38 Nobody Answered the Phone
Jay and Rita are brother and sister.
Hi, Jay, where did you go last night?
I stayed home.
But I called you many times. Nobody answered the phone.
That's impossible.
Oh! Mom probably forgot to pay the phone bill again.
Substitution
No. 1
My girlfriend and I
had a wonderful time last night,
My girlfriend and I had a wonderful time last night,
saw a scary movie last night,
My girlfriend and I saw a scary movie last night.
went to a French restaurant last night
My girlfriend and I went to a French restaurant last night.
No. 2
had some coffee at a nearby cafe,
We had some coffee at a nearby cafe.
had dinner at a local restaurant,
We had dinner at a local restaurant.
had lunch at a cheap snack bar,
We had lunch at a cheap snack bar.