The Bear's whisper
Two travelers John and Bob are walking through a forest
They are best friends
"It's getting dark"
"How much longer must we go, Bob?"
"We are almost there"
"I'm scared, let's hurry"
"Don't be scared John, I'm here"
"But, what if we meet a Lion? Or maybe a bear"
"Don't worry, I'll protect you"
"Really?"
"Of course, we are best friends. right?"
"I'll always protect you"
"Thanks Bob, you are a true friend"
"Come on let's go, we have to go over that hill"
"Bob, let's rest here for a while. I'm tired"
John and Bob decide to rest for a few minutes before going over the hill
"We can rest here for a while"
"But we can't stay too long the sun will go down soon"
"My feet hurt, I'm going to take off my shoes"
John takes off his shoes
Suddenly he hears a strange sound
"Did you hear that Bob?"
"What?"
"I heard a strange sound"
"What strange sound? I didn't hear anything"
"I really heard something"
"What did it sound like?"
"I'm not sure, but it sounded like a bear"
"A bear? that can't be"
"There aren't any bears around here"
"I hope you are right"
The two listen carefully for a while
They don't hear anything
"I told you it's nothing, don't worry"
"Besides If it's a bear, I'll protect you"
"Thanks Bob, you are really brave"
"I'm glad you are my friend"
"I'm your best friend you can always trust me"
"Let's go now John, put on your shoes"
"OK"
John is putting on his shoes
A Bear sees the two
"I'm hungry, I need some food"
"Hey! look over there, my worries are over"
"There is my lunch, and dinner"
The Bear comes out of the bush
"Hello you two, don't run away"
"I'm gonna eat you up"
"Oh my goodness! it's a bear! a real bear!"
Bob runs away quickly by himself
He doesn't think of John
John still doesn't have his shoes on
So he can't run very fast
"Run for your life!"
"Wait for me Bob, I can't run that fast"
"Help me! please!"
Bob doesn't help John
He climbs up a tree by himself
"I can't climb up a tree what shall I do?"
"Maybe I'll pretend to be dead"
"Bears don't eat dead meat"
John pretends to be dead
He just lies down on the ground
"I got you"
"Get up, I know you are not dead"
"Come on, get up"
"Maybe he really is dead"
"He's not moving or breathing"
"But he is warm, I don't understand"
The bear keeps sniffing John
It looks as if the bear was whispering something to John
"Perhaps he's dead, I better just go for now"
The bear leaves John alone and goes
Bob comes down from the tree
"John, Are you OK?"
"I think so, but why didn't you help me?"
"I was going to help"
"But the bear just went away, please forgive me"
"But what did the bear whisper to you?"
"Do you really want to know?"
"Yes, I'm really curious"
"Well, he told me to stay away from you"
"A friend that runs away by himself, is not a true friend"
"I agree with him"
"You are not my true friend, goodbye"
Moral
A friend in need is a friend indeed
The end