白色死亡
White Death
Chapter 1
The woman stood in front of the prison
The prison was a big dirty building in the biggest town of a hot country
The woman was very hot
And she did not like the noise, from all the cars in the road
She was an English woman
And she did not like hot countries, or a lot of noise
She was tall about 50 years old
With blue eyes and a long face
Her face was red, and She looked tired and angry
She knocked at the door of the prison
For a long time nothing happened
Then a little window opened in the door
And a man looked out at her
"Yes, what do you want?"
"I want to see my daughter, It's very important"
"Name?"
"Anna Harland"
"Is that your name? or your daughter's name?"
"It's my name"
"My daughter's name is Sarah Harland"
"You can't visit her today"
"Come back on Wednesday"
"No I came from England to see her today"
"It's very important, She's going to court tomorrow"
"Please take me to her, now"
"Wait a minute"
The little window closed
But the door did not open
The woman waited in front of the door for a long time
A lot of people in the road looked at her
One or two young men laughed
But she did not move
She stood there in the hot road, in front of the prison door
And waited
After 20 minutes, the door opened
"Come with me" the man said
The woman went in with him
It was dark in the prison
And at first, she could not see very well
She walked for a long time, past hundreds of doors
Then the man opened one of them
"In here" he said
"You can have 10 minutes"
Anna Harland walked into the room
And the man went in after her
He closed the door behind him
There was a table in the room, and two chairs
On one of the chairs sat her daughter Sarah
She was a tall girl, about 19 years old, with big blue eyes
"Mother!" she said
"I'm very happy to see you"
And she got up
And began to run across the room to her mother
"Sarah" Anna said. And Put out her arms
But the man moved quickly, and stood between them
"No!" he said to Anna
"I'm sorry, I know you are her mother"
"You can talk, but that's all"
"Please sit down at the table"
"I am here, to watch you"
The mother and daughter sat down at the table
Anna's hands were near Sarah's on the table
She looked carefully at her daughter
Sarah's dress and face were dirty
"She's tired and unhappy" Anna thought
"Sarah, what happened?" she said
"We have 10 minutes to talk, no more"
"Tell me please quickly"
"I want to help you"
Sarah looked at her mother
"Oh mother I'm happy you are here"
"I wanted you to come"
"Mother I... I didn't do it"
"It isn't true, please believe me"
"Of course, I believe you. Sarah"
"But tell me about it, what happened?"
"Quickly begin at the beginning"
"Yes, but... I don't know"
"When did it begin, I don't know"
"I don't understand it"
"Why did the police arrest you?"
"When did they bring you to this prison?"
"Last week, I think. Yes, last week"
"At the airport when we arrived"
"The police stopped us, and looked in our bags"
"Then..." Sarah looked down at the table
"She's crying" Anna thought "She's very unhappy"
"What happened then, Sarah?" her mother asked
"They, They said there were drugs in my bag"
"Then they took me into a room, and told me to take my dress off"
"They looked for more drugs, but they found nothing"
"Then... Then they brought me here"
"I see, where were the drugs then?"
"Where did they find them?"
"Oh, they didn't tell you" Sarah stopped crying
She looked up, and there was a smile on her face
But, it was not a happy smile
"The drugs were in a tube of toothpaste"
"A toothpaste tube with drugs in it"
"Heroin, not toothpaste"
"And you didn't know about it"
"No mother, Of course not"
"Do you think I clean my teeth with heroin"
Anna Harland smiled
It was difficult to smile because she was afraid
But she smiled, because she wanted to help her daughter
"I know you don't clean your teeth with heroin"
"You have very good teeth Sarah"
"But, what about Stephen?"
"Did he know about the heroin?"
"Did he put it in the toothpaste tube?"
"Stephen? No"
"Why do you ask about Stephen, mother?"
"Well, is he in prison too?"
"You said 'us', and 'our' bags"
"Did the police arrest him too?"
"Oh no"
Sarah's face was unhappy
"No, I wasn't with Stephen mother"
"You see, Stephen and I..."
"Well... We aren't friends now"
"I left him about two months ago"
"And then I met Hassan"
"Hassan?"
"Yes, I was with Hassan at the airport"
"Stephen was on the plane too, I don't know why"
"But he wasn't with me. It's Hassan, he was with me"
"Hassan's important to me now, not Stephen"
Anna looked at her daughter "I see"
"And did the police arrest this Hassan too?"
"Is he in prison?"
"Yes, he is"
"They arrested him, but I can't see him"
"I asked them, I wanted to see him"
"But they said no"
"Mother, I'm sure Hassan didn't know about the heroin"
"He's a good man, He didn't know, I'm sure"
"Then why was the heroin in your bag, Sarah?"
"I don't know mother, I don't know"
The man looked at the clock in the room
"I'm sorry Mrs Harland" he said
"But that's 10 minutes. It's time to go"
"Anna Harland stood up slowly"
"Alright" she said
"But don't be afraid" Sarah
"I'm coming to the court tomorrow"
"Yes mother" Sarah said "Thank you"
"The police are bringing Hassan to court tomorrow too. I think"
"You can see him there"
"He's a good man mother"
"And... I'm sure he didn't know about the drugs"
"Perhaps" Anna said
She walked slowly to the door
And then stood by the door, and looked at her daughter again
"Sarah, you are telling me the truth, aren't you?"
Sarah began to cry again
"Yes mother, of course I am"
"I always tell you the truth, you know that"
Anna smiled "Yes Sarah"
She said quietly "Yes I believe you"
She went through the door, and the man went out after her
Sarah sat quietly at the table in the room, and looked at her hands
"Yes" she thought "I told you the truth, mother"
"I always tell you the truth"
"But I didn't tell you everything"
She put her head in her hands
-
Chapter 2
Anna Harland left the prison, and went to talk to the police
She waited a long time, in a small office
But after an hour, a policeman came into the room
He was a big man, about 55 years old
With brown eyes and a nice smile
He moved very slowly and quietly
"Good afternoon, Mrs Harland" he said
"My name is Detective Inspector Aziz"
"I arrested your daughter three days ago"
"I'm very sorry for you"
"This is a very unhappy thing for a mother"
"It's a very unhappy thing for my daughter, Inspector"
Anna said angrily
"Because she didn't do it, she's innocent you know"
"She knows nothing about those drugs"
Detective inspector Aziz looked at her carefully for a minute
He did not know many English women
"She has an interesting face" he thought
"Very blue eyes and a long nose"
"She is not afraid of me, and she is not crying"
"Perhaps she wants to know the truth"
"Perhaps she can help me too"
"Well, Mrs Harland" he said slowly
"It's difficult for me"
"Is your daughter telling the truth?"
"Is she innocent?"
"Because the drugs were in her bag you know"
"I know" Anna said
"But she was with a young man, Hassan"
"She doesn't know him very well, I think"
"Tell me about him please, I want to know"
Inspector Aziz smiled
"All right" he said
"But first, tell me about your daughter"
"Why was she on that plane?"
"Why did she come to this country? tell me"
Anna Harland looked at him
"He's a nice man" she thought
"He listens to people"
"Perhaps he wants to help"
"Perhaps he can understand Sarah"
"Do you have daughters?" she asked
"Yes" The Inspector answered "two"
"Then perhaps you can understand" Anna said
"Sarah is 19"
"She finished school last year"
"And she worked for 6 months in a hospital, to get some money"
"Then she and her boyfriend Stephen visited a lot of countries"
"They went to Greece, Turkey, India, Australia"
"And now they are here"
"They are young, and they want to see new countries"
"And new towns and new people, that's all"
"I see" the Inspector said
"But sometimes, young people do things, bad things"
"Because they are in a different country"
"And they need money"
"Not Sarah" Anna said "And not heroin"
"Sarah worked in a hospital and she knows about heroin"
"She knows it can kill people"
"I'm a doctor, and she wants to be a doctor too"
"I see" Inspector said again
He looked at her and thought, but he said nothing
"Now" Anna said "tell me about this young man Hassan"
"Alright" the inspector said
He took some papers from the table, and began to read to her
"But we don't know very much about him"
"He's a rich boy, from a good family"
"His father has two or three shops I think"
"And the police in his town know him too"
"Last year his father gave him a new car"
"A very fast car, and listen to this..."
"One day he hit a police car"
"And the police car went into the river, what a story"
"His father bought a new car for the police"
"His father has a lot of money"
The Inspector smiled, but Anna looked unhappy
"Oh dear" she said "that's not very good"
"No" he said "It isn't good"
"But this story about the heroin is worse, much worse"
"I don't like this story"
-
Chapter 3
Next morning, Anna Harland went to the court
She was first there
She sat in the courtroom, and waited
A lot of people came in, and she saw a man and his wife
"Perhaps they are Hassan's father and mother" Anna thought
But she did not want to talk to them
The lawyers came in next, with a lot of papers
They sat at a table in front of her, and talked quietly
"Those two lawyers" Anna thought "They are old friends"
"But one of them, wants my daughter to die"
"And one wants her to be free"
After the lawyers the jury came in, twelve people men and women
They sat down and watched the lawyers
They looked at Anna, and then talked quietly about her
"These people don't look very important" she thought
"But they are the most important people here"
"There are going to say 'she did it'"
"Or, 'she didn't do it'"
"And then Sarah comes home to me, or she dies"
She watched their faces carefully
Then some policemen came in
Inspector Aziz saw Anna and smiled at her
But Anna did not talk to him
Because Sarah came in at the same time
She looked afraid, and her face was very white
She looked across the courtroom saw her mother
And gave her an unhappy smile
There were two policemen behind Sarah
But Anna did not looked at them
She looked at the tall dark young man next to Sarah, Hassan
"He's about 20 years old" Anna thought
"He's very tall, but he has a nice face"
"And very beautiful dark eyes"
Sarah likes him, and I can understand that
But he looks very unhappy too, and afraid
His hands are moving all the time
Hassan looked at Sarah and smiled
She smiled back at him
Anna wanted to talk to Sarah
But just then, a policeman said loudly:
"All stand please!"
Everybody stood up and the judge came into the courtroom
He went to his chair, and sat down
The police lawyer began
"These two young people, came into our country last week" he said
"The young man lives in this country"
"And the young woman is English"
"At the airport, the police looked in their bags"
"And they found three tubes of toothpaste"
"These tubes of toothpaste"
He had the three tubes in his hand, and he looked at them
Everybody could see them
"But are they tubes of toothpaste?" he asked
"No! men and women of the jury, they are not"
"Oh no, there is no toothpaste in these tubes"
"There is heroin in them"
"Yes heroin, a bad dirty drug"
"Perhaps the worst drug"
"People die from this drug"
"The 'white death' they call it"
The lawyer stopped and looked at the jury
He waited for a minute or two
The courtroom was very quiet
Then he began again
"But why, you ask me"
"Why did these two young people have this heroin in their bags?"
"I can't tell you"
"Because heroin is one of the most expensive drugs, too"
"They can sell these tubes of heroin in our country"
"For perhaps 80,000 pounds, 80,000 pounds! easy money!"
"And, men and women of the jury, many people in our country"
"Young people, schoolchildren, too take this drug"
"At first it's exciting, and they feel happy"
"But then they need more and more heroin"
"And they need more money to buy the drug"
"They leave their homes and families"
"They take more heroin and more, they can't stop"
"Soon the drug begins to kill them"
"And in the end, they die"
"The white death"
"It's not a quick death, and it's not an easy death"
"Yes, men and women of the jury"
"Many young people and children"
"Your children and my children remember, die because of this drug"
"The Lawyer stopped again, the jury watched him and waited"
"He's very good" Anna thought "very very good"
"He's telling the jury an exciting story, and they like him"
"But it isn't good for Sarah"
The lawyer walked across the courtroom, and stood in front of the jury
"But my friends" he said to the jury
"We have a law in this country, and the law is not difficult to understand"
"When people bring heroin into this country, they bring death too"
"We need to stop these people, and how can we do that?"
"The answer is easy, the law for these people is death"
The lawyer walked back to his table
"Now, please look at these two young people here in this court"
He said to the jury
"They brought heroin into this country"
"The airport police are going to tell you about it"
"Please listen carefully it's not a long story"
"And remember the law is death"
The police lawyer sat down
And an airport policeman went to the front of the courtroom
Anna felt ill. She looked at Sarah
Sarah was white-faced and very afraid
Anna closed her eyes
"Sarah" she thought "Oh Sarah"
The police lawyer stood up again
"Please tell the court about Sarah Harland and Hassan"
He said to the airport policeman
"Yes sir" said the policeman
"I found two tubes of toothpaste in the girl's bag"
"And one tube in the young man's bag"
"All three tubes had heroin in them"
"Thank you" the police lawyer sat down
And Mr Chen Sarah's and Hassan's lawyer stood up
"What did Sarah Harland say, when you found the heroin?" he asked
"Nothing sir, she began to cry"
"I see, was she afraid?"
The policeman thought for a minute
"I don't know sir, perhaps she was yes"
"And she said nothing? are you sure?"
The policeman thought again
"Well yes sir, I think perhaps she said..."
"This isn't my toothpaste, this is all wrong"
"I see, and what about the young man Hassan?"
"What did he say?"
"Well sir, He was very angry"
"He said, it's not heroin, that's not true, you put it there"
"I see, thank you"
"Now tell me why did you look in these two young people's bags?"
"You don't usually look in everyone's bags, there isn't time"
The policeman thought again "Well, no sir, we don't"
"I... I'm afraid I can't tell you sir"
"What did you say?" Mr Chen asked very angrily
"Of course you can tell me, this is a court of law"
He looked at judge
This is a very important question, we need an answer
The judge looked at the airport policeman
"I'm sorry" he said
"Please answer the question, the court needs to know the answer"
"Yes sir, well... you see, there was a telephone call"
"Someone telephoned me before the plane arrived"
"The telephone caller said 'there's some heroin on the plane'"
"A young man and a young woman are carrying it"
"I see" Mr Chen said.
He smiled "That's very interesting"
"And who made this telephone call?"
"I don't know" the policeman said
"It was a man, and he talked in English. I don't know his name"
Suddenly Anna heard a noise.
She looked behind her at the door of the courtroom
A tall young man came into the back of the room
Anna knew him at once, it was Stephen, Sarah's old boyfriend
A policeman took him to a chair near Anna
He saw Anna and for a second he looked afraid
But then he smiled and sat down next to her
"Mrs Harland" he said quietly
"It's good to see you, when did you arrived?"
"Yesterday" she said "Why are you late?"
"I couldn't find the court" he answered.
He looked very unhappy
"Tell me how to help?" he said
"I want to help Sarah, but what can I do?"
"I was on the plane too, but I couldn't help her"
"I don't want her to die"
"Stay with me, young man" Anna said quietly
"We can help her, I'm sure we can"
Later that morning, Sarah went to the front of the courtroom
Her face was very white, and her eyes were red with crying
Her lawyer Mr Chen began to ask her questions
"Now Miss Harland why did you come to this country?"
He asked quietly and smiled at her
"Because I like going to different countries, I want to meet new people"
"And why were you with this young man?"
"Because..." Sarah stopped and looked down at her feet
Nobody could see her face
She began again very quietly, but nobody could hear her
"I'm sorry we can't hear you, can you say that again please?"
Sarah looked up
She looked quickly at her mother, And then at Hassan
"Because I love him"
Anna felt old and tired
She looked at the tall young man with the beautiful dark eyes
"It was his heroin" she thought "I'm sure It was"
"He buys and sells heroin and he put it in my daughter's bag"
"And now she says she loves him"
Stephen sat next to her
He did not move, and he watched Sarah all the time
But she did not look at him
Mr Chen waited a minute, and then he questioned Sarah again
"Did you know about the heroin in those tubes of toothpaste?" he asked
"No" Sarah said quickly "Of course I didn't"
"And what about Hassan? did he know about the heroin?"
"Please think about your answer"
"No I'm sure he didn't know, it wasn't our heroin"
Sarah's blue eyes were angry
"We didn't put the heroin in the toothpaste tubes, we are innocent"
"Thank you Miss Harland" Mr Chen said quietly and sat down
The police lawyer stood up
"Miss Harland, how much money did you have in your bag?"
"Um... about... 50 pounds I think"
"That's not very much, this is an expensive country you know"
"How much can you buy? with your 50 pounds"
Sarah did not have an answer
"Um... I don't know" she began
"I usually live very cheaply"
"Did you need more money?"
The Lawyer's questions came quickly now
"Of course you needed more money, you wanted to sell that heroin"
"You wanted to be rich, is that right?"
"No no, that's not true"
The lawyer said nothing for a minute
He looked at the jury and smiled
Then he said
"Do you think toothpaste is very expensive in this country, Miss Harland?"
"Oh no, I don't think. oh I don't know"
"Well, I can tell you. it isn't"
"Toothpaste is cheap here"
"So why did you bring three tubes of toothpaste with you?"
"How often do you clean your teeth, Miss Harland?"
"Six times a day? Or seven? Or eight times a day, perhaps..."
Sarah looked very unhappy
"No I don't know, Hassan..."
"Yes" the lawyer said quickly "Hassan"
"Are you going to say 'Hassan gave it to me'?"
"You love this young man, but you don't want to die"
"Nobody wants to die"
"And now you are going to say 'It was Hassan's toothpaste'"
"Is that your answer, Miss Harland?"
"No" Sarah said angrily "Of course not"
"It was my toothpaste, but..."
"Thank you, Miss Harland"
The police lawyer sat down "I have no more questions"
-
Chapter 4
At 1 o'clock, the judge left the court for an hour
Anna Harland talked to Sarah for ten minutes
Sarah cried at first
"I don't like that police lawyer" she said
"Those questions were very difficult, I couldn't answer them"
"It doesn't matter" her mother said
"Your lawyer Mr Chen is very good"
"And Stephen is here too, now"
"We are all going to help you"
Sarah was angry
"Don't talk to me about Stephen" she said
"I don't like him"
"I don't want to see him here"
"But Sarah he was your boyfriend for two years"
"He wants to help you"
Sarah began to cry again
"Perhaps he does want to help me, I don't know"
"But he's different now, mother"
"You don't understand"
"His eyes are different, they are... I don't know"
"And he can't sit quietly and talk to people now"
"His body is moving all the time"
"He came to see me in our hotel"
"The night before we came to this country, and..."
"I didn't like him mother"
"Why is he here?"
"He doesn't love me now, And I don't love him"
Anna listened carefully to her daughter
And then she went to see Mr Chen and Inspector Aziz
Stephen went with her
"Who made that phone call to the police, at the airport?" she asked
"We need to know that"
"Yes" Mr Chen said "That's very important"
"Can the police tell us?"
"Perhaps" the Inspector said
"But it's very difficult, It was not a long telephone call"
"And the man didn't give his name"
"Perhaps he was a policeman, and he knew about the heroin"
"Perhaps" Mr Chen said
"But then, perhaps he put the heroin there"
"And he wanted the police to find it"
"Perhaps someone doesn't like your daughter, Mrs Harland"
"I don't know" Anna said slowly "But perhaps..."
But then the judge came back into the courtroom
And everybody stopped talking
The judge then called Hassan
Hassan stood up and went to the front of the courtroom
"He's a rich boy" Anna thought
"That shirt and those shoes are very expensive"
Hassan stood there, tall and very quiet
He waited for the questions
He did not look afraid
But when Mr Chen looked at his papers
And asked the first question
Hassan closed his eyes
"Did you know about the heroin in those tubes of toothpaste?"
"No sir"
"Did Sarah know?"
"Who bought the toothpaste"
Hassan closed his eyes again for two or three seconds
Then he answered "I did sir"
"You did, You're sure of that?"
"Yes sir, I'm sure"
"I clean my teeth a lot, you see"
Hassan smiled for a moment
"Well, he does have very white teeth" Anna thought
"Sarah"  Hassan began, then he stopped
"Yes?"
Again Hassan closed his eyes and waited for a second
Then he looked at the jury and said very loudly:
"Sarah did not buy the toothpaste, I bought it"
"I bought all three tubes of toothpaste"
"It was my toothpaste"
Anna sat up in her chair, And looked carefully at Hassan
"That's interesting" she thought "Perhaps he does love Sarah"
"I see" Mr Chen said
"And when did you first meet Sarah Harland?"
"About two months ago, I was in Australia"
"We were in the same hotel"
"She had... a difficult time with her boyfriend"
"And I helped her"
Anna looked at Stephen, he was very angry
And he hit the chair in front of him with his hand
"I see" Mr Chen said again
Then he asked his next question
"Do you usually carry a lot of money?"
"How much money did you have at the airport?"
"About 80 pounds I think"
"That's OK"
"When I need more money I get some work for a week or two"
"We don't need much money"
"And do you sometimes take heroin?"
"No sir, never"
"Thank you, stay there please"
Mr Chen sat down
And the police lawyer stood up
He smiled at Hassan, But it was not a nice smile
"Now Hassan, You bought the toothpaste"
"But it was in Miss Harland's bag, why?"
"Why did she carry it for you"
"Or do you always ask your women to carry things for you?"
He smiled, Hassan said nothing
The lawyer began again
"You had 80 pounds you say"
"But 80,000 pounds... is better than 80 pounds, I think"
"What do you think?"
"Of course It is, but I don't sell heroin"
"It's wrong to sell heroin"
The lawyer moved his papers on the table
He looked at the jury
"So, you are a very good young man"
"With very clean teeth but no money"
"You met a young English girl"
"She was unhappy with her boyfriend"
"So you helped her and took her away with you"
"Is that right?"
"Oh dear! It's not a very good story, you know"
"I don't believe it"
"And I don't think the jury believes it, young man"
He stopped for a minute
Then he looked at Hassan and said loudly:
"You don't love Sarah Harland, And she doesn't love you"
"You went with her because, she could help you"
"And she went with you because she wanted the money"
"She carry the heroin for you to sell"
"That's right isn't it?"
"You put the heroin in the toothpaste tubes"
"And she knew about it"
"Is that the true story, young man? I think it is"
"No I..." Hassan began angrily
But the lawyer did not listen
He sat down
"I have no more questions" he said to the judge
-
Chapter 5
The judge looked at his papers, and then at the jury
"It is now 4 o'clock in the afternoon" he said
"We can begin again in the morning"
"Please be here at 10 o'clock"
The judge stood up and left the courtroom
The jury left too
And the police took Sarah and Hassan back to the prison
Anna looked at Stephen
"Well young man" she said "What can we do now?"
"We have 16 hours, before tomorrow morning"
"I don't know" Stephen said
He looked at her for a minute
Then he looked away over her head at the front of the court
"I'm sure, Hassan knew about the heroin" he said
"He put it in her bag, I'm sure he did"
"Sarah is innocent, but he isn't"
Mr Chen came and stood with them
"She's innocent" Stephen said again "But Hassan's going to die"
Mr Chen looked at Stephen carefully
"Perhaps" he said slowly
"But did you listen to Hassan in court?"
"He said 'Sarah did not buy the toothpaste, It was my toothpaste'"
"Now why did he say that?"
"It was not an easy thing to say, you know?"
"What is the jury going to think about it?"
"It doesn't matter" Stephen said angrily
"Because it wasn't toothpaste, And he didn't buy it in a shop"
"He made those tubes, Because he wanted to sell the heroin"
"And he's going to die"
"That's the law in this country"
Anna looked at Stephen and said nothing
"He's very angry" she thought
"His face is red, and he's talking very quickly"
"Does he want to kill Hassan?'
"And what's the matter with his eyes?"
Mr Chen watched Stephen too
"But who made that telephone call?"
"It's important and I want to know" he said
"I'm going to ask the police now"
"Would you like to come with me, Mrs Harland?"
"Yes, Of course" Anna said
"Stephen are you coming?"
"Yes, ah... no no" Stephen said
"I'm going to meet a man, I think he can help us"
"Alright" Anna said
"But when can I meet you?"
"I need to talk to you about Hassan"
"Can I come to your hotel tonight?"
"Ah... no, not tonight" Stephen said quickly
His face was now white, And he looked tired and ill
His hands and body moved all the time
"Come to my hotel tomorrow morning, bye"
He walked quickly out of the courtroom
Anna and Mr Chen watched him
Inspector Aziz was near the door
And he watched Stephen too
-
Chapter 6
Anna and Mr Chen talked to the police
But the police could tell them nothing more about the telephone call to the airport
Inspector Aziz telephoned two or three people
And then, he talked to Anna again
When Anna left Inspector Aziz, she was much happier
Then she went to the prison to see Sarah
The man took her to Sarah's room
Anna and Sarah sat at the table
And the man stood and watched
"It was a bad day mother, I'm sorry" Sarah said slowly
Her eyes were not red now, But she looked very tired
Her hands were near her mother's on the table
"It wasn't a very good day, that's true" Anna said
"But you have a very good lawyer you know"
"The Jury likes him"
"But it doesn't help" Sarah said
"There was heroin in the toothpaste tubes"
"And the tubes were in my bag"
"What can Mr Chen do?"
"The heroin was in my bag mother"
"The jury knows that"
Anna looked at her daughter carefully
"Perhaps Hassan put it there Sarah" she said
"You like him I know, And he looks nice, but..."
"Mother I love him, I said that in court, you heard me"
"And Hassan loves me too"
"And he does not buy or sell heroin. I..."
Sarah stopped talking, And put her hands on her stomach
"What's the matter?" Anna asked
She looked at the man
"Quickly she's ill get a doctor"
The man ran from the room
And Anna put her arms round her daughter
She waited, and then Sarah sat up
"It's alright, mother" she said
Her face was very white, but she looked a little better
"It happens sometimes, I often feel ill"
"And I don't like to eat much, But it's not very bad"
"I think I'm going to stay alive, because of it"
She gave her mother a smile
"What? What are you saying?"
"What are you talking about?" Anna cried
"My baby"
Sarah's face looked different now
Half smiling half afraid
"Mother, don't be angry please"
"I'm going to have a baby, It's Hassan's baby"
"I.. We wanted to come to England"
"And tell you about it there, but now we can't"
"I love him, and he wants to be my husband, mother"
"Mother please don't be angry"
Anna's face was white now
For nearly a minute, she could say nothing
She wanted to cry, but she didn't
At last she said "Oh Sarah"
"What's going to happen to this baby?"
Sarah looked at her hands "Nothing, mother"
"I asked Mr Chen about that"
"They can't kill me, you see"
"Because I'm going to have a baby"
"They can't kill a mother and her baby"
"That's the law, but..."
"That doesn't help Hassan"
Anna heard a noise and looked at the door
"Listen Sarah" she said quickly "Before the doctor comes..."
"I'm not angry, and I do love you Sarah, Of course"
"But listen, I talked to Inspector Aziz, again today"
"I think he can help you and Hassan too"
"So don't be afraid, Please and..." the door opened
And the man came in with a woman doctor
Anna stood up, she took Sarah's hand
"I'm going now Sarah, but don't be afraid"
"You are going to be alright, I'm sure of it"
-
Chapter 7
Next morning, at half past four
Anna Harland stood in a quiet road in front of a hotel
She waited, and then she heard a car behind the hotel
The car doors opened and closed
She waited quietly and then looked down the road
A man walked into the road, and stood next to a shop
He did not look at Anna, but Anna looked at him, and smiled
Then she walked into the hotel
She went upstairs, and knocked on the door of a bedroom
A man answered
"Who is it?"
"It's me, Stephen" she said
"Anna Harland. Open the door please, I want to talk to you"
The door opened, and Stephen looked out slowly
"Anna?"
"What are you doing here, at this time? It's..."
Anna walked quickly into the room
"Yes, It's half past four"
"Sarah is in court again, at 10 o'clock"
"I need your help young man, Please get up"
"But what can I do?"
Anna looked at him
"You went to see a man last night, What happened?"
"Can he help Sarah?"
Stephen answered slowly, he did not looked at Anna
"No, I'm sorry, he can't"
Anna was cold and angry, "I see" she said
"Well, can you and I help her then?"
"Tell me Stephen, what do you know about Hassan?"
"Hassan?" Stephen said angrily
"Well, we met him in Australia and Sarah, went away with him"
"She doesn't understand him, but I do"
"He's a rich young man with a beautiful body"
"He likes playing with girls, But he doesn't love her"
"And do you love her, Stephen?"
Stephen did not answer at once
For two or three seconds Anna waited
"He doesn't know" she thought "He can't answer the question"
"Yes Mrs Harland, Of course I love her"
"But he's not looking at me" Anna thought
"He's looking out of the window"
"He's not thinking about Sarah"
"Stephen" Anna asked quietly
"Did you go to see Sarah and Hassan in Australia, The night before they came to this country?"
Stephen looked up at her
"Ah... yes, I went to their hotel" he said
"I asked Sarah to leave Hassan, and come back to me"
"But how did you know that?"
"Sarah told me of course. Was Hassan there?"
"No he..." Stephen stopped
Then he said "why do you ask?"
Anna opened her handbag
"Look at this" she said
"What is it? Do you know?"
He looked at it, and then at Anna
"A tube of toothpaste, why?"
"That's right, a policeman gave it to me"
"And he took it from a man"
"You met that man, last night Stephen"
"You gave him ten tubes of toothpaste"
"What was in those tubes of toothpaste Stephen?"
Stephen said nothing
He looked at the toothpaste and stood up
But Anna was between him and the door
She gave the toothpaste to him
"Would you like to clean your teeth, Stephen?"
He began to move to the door, but Anna took his arm
"You don't love Sarah. Do you Stephen?"
"You hate her, because she left you"
"You put three of these tubes in Sarah's bag"
"And then you phoned the police"
"You told them about the tubes in my daughter's bag"
"You want Sarah to die"
"No" Stephen said "No no, not Sarah. Hassan!"
"I put them in Hassan's bag, not Sarah's"
"I wanted Hassan to die"
He opened the door quickly, and then stopped
A man stood there, Inspector Aziz
He put his hand on Stephen's arm
"It's an old story young man" he said "It happens everyday"
"My first girlfriend left me for a new man"
"I was very angry too, I hated him"
"But I didn't want to kill him"
"Come on let's go"
"You can tell your story to the judge"
-
Chapter 8
At 11 o'clock that morning
Sarah and Hassan were free
Sarah stood with her mother, Inspector Aziz, and Mr Chen
She smiled happily
"Mother you are wonderful"
"Now, I can be happy"
"But how did you know about Stephen?"
Inspector Aziz answered:
"Young woman" he said "Remember, your mother is a doctor"
"She knew Stephen was ill, Because of his eyes and his body"
"His eyes are very big and dark, And his body is always moving"
"Well, yes" Anna said "But you helped me, Sarah"
"You said he was different, remember?"
"And I looked at him carefully, and began to think"
"Heroin does that to people"
"He did a very bad thing" Sarah said slowly
"But I feel sorry for him now"
"When is he going to court, Inspector?"
"I don't know" the Inspector said "In two weeks perhaps"
"But don't think about him"
"Would you like to see our beautiful country, Mrs Harland?"
"Where would you like to go?"
Anna smiled at him
"Thank you, but I can't stay"
"Tomorrow, I'm going back to England"
"To talk to Stephen's mother and father"
Inspector Aziz looked at her, and said nothing for a minute
Then he said quietly
"Yes, I feel very sorry for them"
"It kills a lot of young people, this heroin"
"Yes, but it isn't going to kill my daughter"
"She isn't going to die now"
Anna took Sarah's hand
"So thank you again Inspector Aziz and Mr Chen"
"And goodbye"
"Now I'm going to have a long cold drink, in a quiet garden"
"With my daughter, and her new young man"
"I want to know a lot more about him"
Hassan stood with his mother and father near the door of the court
Anna Harland put her hand on her daughter's arm
And smiled at them
The end