Hi everyone, I'm Lisa. Hey guys I'm John
Today we will learn how to ask for directions
Ok, how to ask for directions
So now we're going to listen to the dialog three times
-
Excuse I'm lost, where's the supermarket?
Oh hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left next to the movie theater
Okay, I understand thank you
-
Excuse me, I'm lost, where's the supermarket?
Oh hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left next to the movie theater
Okay, I understand thank you
-
Excuse me, I'm lost, where's the supermarket?
Oh hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left, next to the movie theater
Oh I understand, thank you
-
Okay, so I'm lost on the street
I'm lost, so I don't know where I am
I'm lost, so I should walk south, for five minutes
Right walk south, so do you know "south"?
"North, south, east, west. Walk south"
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Right, when you get near the hospital
So, you can see the hospital, it's close
Yeah, you can see the street, So, turn right
So, take a right, can also be turn right
Right, turn right = take a right
Go straight, and then it will be on your left next to the movie theater
It will be on your left. Uh hum
So, you will see it on your left
Right okay, on your left, next to the movie theater
Next to, like very close to, or beside
Right, beside the movie theater = close to the movie theater
Okay, let's listen to the dialog again, three more times
Okay
-
Excuse Me, I'm lost, where's the supermarket?
Oh hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left next to the movie theater
Okay, I understand, thank you
-
Excuse me, I'm lost, where's the supermarket?
Oh hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left, next to the movie theater
Okay, I understand thank you
-
Excuse me, I'm lost, where's the super market?
Oh, hello, walk south for five minutes
Okay
Then take a right, when you get near the hospital
Uh huh
Go straight, and then it will be on your left next to the movie theater
Okay, I understand, thank you
-
If this is difficult for you it's okay
Don't worry, just listen again, and again
You need more practice, you can do it
Thank you for listening, I'm john. And I'm Lisa
Bye. Bye bye
The end